Inventory of the Ginetta Sagan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Aurora Foundation, 1988-1993
  - Croatia correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 201: 3)
  - Vietnam research materials, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 201: 4)
  - Tom Lantos correspondence and clippings, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 201: 5-6)
    Relates to congressional testimony on Kuwait
  - "Vietnam: From Human Rights Victim to Victimizer," by GS, circa 1988 (Box-folder 201: 7)
- Biographical file, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 201: 8-9)
  Contains clippings and photograph of GS with Sting and others
- I sommersi e i salvati, by Primo Levi, photocopy, 1986 (Box-folder 201: 10)
- Personal correspondence and notes, 1988, undated (Box-folder 201: 11)
  Includes Sara Paasche letters
- Amnesty International, 1972-1995
  - Greece correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 202: 1)
    Relates mainly to prisoner Grigoris Farakos
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 202: 2)
  - Internal documents and correspondence, 1978-1995 (Box-folder 202: 3)
  - GS letter to Ivan Morris on AIUSA's activities, 1976 (Box-folder 202: 4)
- Aurora Foundation routine correspondence and internal documents, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 202: 5-6)
- Biographical file, 1940s-1993
  - Clippings, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 202: 7)
  - "Ginetta Sagan: A Profile," by Robin Dorman, 1993 (Box-folder 202: 8)
  - Italian trip itinerary, 1995 May (Box-folder 202: 9)
  - Photographs of GS, Rose Styron, Leonard Bernstein, Amalia Fleming, Lidia Ghielmetti, 1940s-1991 (Box-folder 202: 10)
- Personal correspondence, 1986-1995
  - 1994 (Box-folder 202: 11)
    Includes William Schulz and Joan Baez
  - Letters of gratitude, invitations, and greeting cards, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 202: 12)
  - Women's International Center, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 202: 13)
- New York Times letter to the editor by GS, 1995 July 28 (Box-folder 202: 14)
- Writings by others, 1988-1995
  - Václav Havel speech at Frankfurt Book Fair, 1989 (Box-folder 202: 15)
  - Nguyen Si Binh speech in San Jose, 1993 August 8 (Box-folder 202: 16)
  - William Ratliff articles on Argentina and Amnesty International, 1988, undated (Box-folder 202: 17)
  - Leonard Sagan reports on trips to Italy, 1991, 1995 (Box-folder 202: 18)
- Human rights printed matter and clippings, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 202: 19-21)
- Amnesty International, 1982, 1994-1996
  - Board of Directors meeting agendas, memoranda, and reports, 1996 (Box-folder 203: 1)
  - Board of Directors nomination for GS, 1982 (Box-folder 203: 2)
  - Correspondence (William Schulz, Charles Henry, Charles Shattuck, Tom Lantos and others), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 203: 3)
    Includes photograph of Joan Baez
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence and internal documents, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 203: 4-5)
- Personal correspondence, 1988, 1993-1996
  - Letters of gratitude, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 203: 6)
  - Leonard Sagan, 1988 July (Box-folder 203: 7)
- Jefferson Awards press coverage, 1986 December (Box-folder 203: 8)
- Speeches and writings by GS, 1990s
  - Stanford Medical School commencement address by GS, 1996 (Box-folder 203: 9)
  - Notes on Vietnam, Cambodia, and women in the resistance movement of World War II, 1990s (Box-folder 203: 10)
- Africa and Vietnam printed matter, 1994 (Box-folder 203: 11)
- Human rights clippings, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 203: 12-13)
- Harry Bridges: A Man and His Union, video tape, 1993 (Box-folder 203: 14)
- Office of Strategic Services incoming message on the Italian resistance, photocopy from the U.S. National Archives, 1945 March 31 (Box-folder 204: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1994-1996
  - Board of Directors memoranda, agendas, and reports, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 204: 2-3)
  - Internal documents and correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 204: 4)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund press releases, correspondence and printed matter, 1995 (Box-folder 204: 5)
  - Printed matter, 1996 (Box-folder 204: 6)
  - GS notes on human rights violations, 1994 (Box-folder 204: 7)
- Stanford Commencement file, 1996 (Box-folder 204: 8)
  Includes letter of invitation, program, and photograph of GS
- Personal letters received, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 204: 9)
  Includes letter from Leo Valiani
- Leonard Sagan writings, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 204: 10)
  Includes article on torture in Italy
- Human rights clippings, 1996 (Box-folder 204: 11-12)
- Appointment calendars, 1972, 1974-1975, 1977, 1983 (Box-folder 204: 13)
- Amnesty International report, undated (Box-folder 204: 14)
  Five 3.5" computer disks
- "Gstaad, Vietnam, some resistance," compact sound cassette, 1994 November (Box-folder 204: 15)
- Amnesty International, 1973-1996
  - Correspondence regarding Vietnam, 1979-1994 (Box-folder 205: 1)
  - Newsletters, internal documents, and reports, 1973-1996 (Box-folder 205: 2-3)
- Vietnam research materials, 1986-1996
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 205: 4)
  - Printed matter, research materials, and notes, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 205: 5-6)
    Includes translation of interview with Vo Nguyen Giap
  - Reports, 1980s (Box-folder 205: 7)
- Biographical file, 1982-1996 (Box-folder 205: 8-10)
  Includes clippings and photographs of GS with Bill Clinton, Lech Wałęsa, Elena Nightingale, and at the Stanford commencement
- Correspondence, 1977-1996
  - François Ponchaud, Noam Chomsky, and Robert Silvers, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 205: 11)
  - Geyelin, Philip, 1982 April 15 (Box-folder 205: 12)
  - Valiani, Leo, 1996 (Box-folder 205: 13)
- "Lea Ottolenghi, Remembrances and Impressions of a Refugee,", 1989 (Box-folder 205: 14)
  On the Italian resistance
- Vietnam and Africa printed matter, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 205: 15)
- Sound recordings, 1986-1992, undated
  Compact sound cassette. Listed by label
  - "Historical record. Gianna. Interrogation. Sondrio. Como. Brigate Nere,", 1991 (Box 206)
  - "Historical review, events 1943/1945,", 1992 May (Box 206)
  - "Interview with Nancy Flowers,", undated (Box 206)
  - "Memo for International Secretariat,", 1986 July (Box 206)
    Microcassette
  - "Vietnam,", undated (Box 206)
- Amnesty International, 1982-1995
  - Internal documents, correspondence, and printed matter, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 206: 1)
  - Bosnia research material, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 206: 2)
  - East Timor research materials, 1982 (Box-folder 206: 3)
- Aurora Foundation press releases and research proposal, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 206: 4)
- Biographical file, 1974-1995
  - Ginetta Sagan Day clipping and correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 206: 5)
  - Clipping and Jefferson Awards pamphlet, 1987, 1995 (Box-folder 206: 6)
  - Photographs, 1974-1995
    - GS with Rose Styron, 1986 (Box-folder 206: 7)
    - Joan Baez with Jimmy Carter, Zbigniew Romaszewski, and GS at first Western Regional Conference of AI, 1974-1995 (Box-folder 206: 8)
- Personal correspondence, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 206: 9-11)
  Includes letters from Joan Baez, Joan Bridge Baez, Diablo Valley College, and others
- Memorandum from Emilio Q. Daddario to Richard Massarini on the Italian socialist party, 1945 June 27 (Box-folder 206: 12)
  Photocopy from the National Archives
- Humanitas press releases and statements on Vietnam, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 206: 13)
- Mauthausen concentration camp pamphlet, 1970s (Box-folder 206: 14)
- Human rights clippings, 1981-1982, 1993 (Box-folder 206: 15)
- Presidential Medal of Freedom ceremony, video tape, 1996 September 9 (Box-folder 207: 1)
- Address book, undated (Box-folder 207: 2)
- Amnesty International, 1983-1995
  - A History and Atlas of Human Rights, compact disc, 1994 (Box-folder 207: 3)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund, 1995 (Box-folder 207: 4)
  - Internal documents and correspondence on Algeria and Carlos Noya Murrati, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 207: 5)
  - Printed matter, 1995 (Box-folder 207: 6)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 207: 7)
- Biographical file, 1995 (Box-folder 207: 8)
  Includes questionnaire for Jing Lyman Lecture series
- Photographs, 1980s-1990s
  - Joan Baez in Poland at a Solidarity rally, 1986 (Box-folder 207: 9)
  - GS with Rose Styron, Lidia Ghielmetti, Jack Healey, and Romaszewskis, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 207: 10)
  - Amnesty International event and trip to Poland, 1986 (Box-folder 207: 11)
- Personal correspondence with Cosette Thompson, Leonard Sagan, Colman McCarthy, Lidia Ghielmetti, and William Schulz, 1995 (Box-folder 207: 12)
- Human rights clippings, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 207: 13)
- Yugoslav News Bulletin, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 207: 14)
- Amnesty International, 1994-1996
  - Internal correspondence and printed matter, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 208: 1)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund fundraising documents, correspondence, and printed matter, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 208: 2-3)
    Includes Jimmy Carter letter to Joan Baez
- Aurora Foundation, 1991-1996
  - Nguyen Chi Thien correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 208: 4)
  - Routine correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 208: 5)
- Photographs of GS at Stanford Medical School commencement, 1996 June (Box-folder 208: 6)
- Correspondence, 1974-1996
  - Fleming, Amalia, 1974 July 23 (Box-folder 208: 7)
  - Personal (Giannes Koutsocheras, Mary Peace Finley, Helen Harkins, Walter Reich, Lidia Ghielmetti, and others), 1977-1996 (Box-folder 208: 8)
    Includes photographs of GS cooking
- Notes by GS, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 208: 9)
- Human rights clippings, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 208: 10-12)
- Amnesty International, 1994-1996
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 209: 1)
  - Internal documents and printed matter, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 209: 2)
- Aurora Foundation mission statement and routine correspondence, 1992 (Box-folder 209: 3)
- Biographical file, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 209: 4-5)
  Contains clippings and a copy of The Matchbox, a children's book about GS, by Mary Peace Finley
- Correspondence, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 209: 6)
  Includes invitation, postcards, and letters of congratulations
- Commencement speech by GS at Stanford Medical School, 1996 June 16 (Box-folder 209: 7-8)
- Embroidered handkerchief, undated (Box-folder 209: 9)
- Nguyen Chi Thien autographed books, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 209: 10)
- Human rights clippings, 1986, 1996 (Box-folder 209: 11)
- Amnesty International, 1981-1996
  - Correspondence, internal documents, and notes, 1981-1996 (Box-folder 210: 1-3)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, press releases, and printed matter, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 210: 4-6)
- Nguyen Van Canh and Vu Tran correspondence, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 210: 7)
- Biographical clippings, 1996 (Box-folder 210: 8-9)
- Humanitas correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 210: 10)
  Letters to Joan Baez in response to her Vietnam editorial
- Personal correspondence (Joan Baez, Elena Nightingale, Barbara Piasecka Johnson, Cosette Thompson, and others), 1970-1996 (Box-folder 210: 11-12)
- Notes by GS for speech, 1990s (Box-folder 210: 13)
- Vietnam research materials, 1978-1993 (Box-folder 210: 14-15)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1990s (Box-folder 210: 16-18)
- Amnesty International correspondence (Paula Dobriansky, William Schulz, Patrizia Nuvolari, and Barbara Piasecka Johnson), 1994-1996 (Box-folder 211: 1-3)
  Relates mainly to Ginetta Sagan Fund
- Aurora Foundation, 1982-1995
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1993 December 16 (Box-folder 211: 4)
  - Internal correspondence, 1982-1995 (Box-folder 211: 5)
- Speeches and writings by GS, 1973-1995
  - Book proposal on the Italian resistance, 1990s (Box-folder 211: 6)
  - Palo Alto Times letter to the editor, notes on Guido Bustelli, and a description of her 1945 rescue, 1973-1995 (Box-folder 211: 7)
- Personal correspondence, 1991-1995
  - Ghielmetti, Lidia, 1991 July 22 (Box-folder 211: 8)
  - Styron, Rose, 1992 (Box-folder 211: 9)
    Includes poems by Joan Baez
  - Jing Lyman Lecture correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 211: 10)
  - Invitation to Ginetta Sagan Fund luncheon, 1994 (Box-folder 211: 11)
  - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 211: 12)
    Includes correspondence from Istituto storico della Resistenza and Elena Nightingale. Mainly in Italian
- Photographs of GS at Amnesty fundraisers, 1983, undated (Box-folder 211: 13)
- Joan Baez caricatures of GS, photocopies, 1990s (Box-folder 211: 14)
- "Bruce Hobson's parole hearing," audiocassette, 1977 November 8 (Box-folder 211: 15)
- Human rights printed matter and clippings, mainly on Vietnam, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 211: 16-18)
- Amnesty International, 1974-1976, 1994-1995
  - Algeria subject file, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 212: 1)
  - Internal correspondence (William Schulz, Ivan Morris, Barbara Piasecka Johnson), 1974-1976, 1994 (Box-folder 212: 2-3)
  - International Committee Agenda, 1994 October 1 (Box-folder 212: 4)
- Aurora Foundation letters received, printed matter, and press releases, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 212: 5-7)
- Vietnam research materials, 1976-1996 (Box-folder 212: 8)
  Clippings, press releases and correspondence
- Joan Baez, Gloria Lane, Elena Danielson, Albert Schweitzer Institute, and Carl M. Freeman correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 212: 9-11)
- Speeches and writings by GS, 1973, 1993-1995
  - Autobiographical writings on her experience in the Italian resistance, 1973, 1995 (Box-folder 212: 12)
    Includes an incomplete chronology
  - "Setting a Price on Democracy,", 1993-1995 (Box-folder 212: 13)
- "Eastern Europe in 1990: A Trip Report" by LS, 1990 April 18 (Box-folder 212: 14)
- Photographs of Nguyen Chi Thien and Lidia Ghielmetti, 1990s (Box-folder 212: 15-16)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 212: 17-18)
- Amnesty International, 1989-1995
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 213: 1)
  - Internal correspondence (Jack Healey, William Schulz, Cosette Thompson and others), 1992-1995 (Box-folder 213: 2)
    Includes photograph of Nguyen Chi Thien
  - Iraq subject file, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 213: 3)
- Aurora Foundation, 1988-1992
  - Correspondence (Martin Lipset, Dean Dresser, Zbigniew Romaszewski, Andras Nagy, Barbara Piasecka Johnson, and others), 1988-1992 (Box-folder 213: 4-5)
  - GS's letter to the Board on prisoners of conscience in Vietnam, 1992 July 16 (Box-folder 213: 6)
  - Mandate, 1992 March 28 (Box-folder 213: 7)
- Biographical file, 1992, 1995
  - Ginetta Sagan Day proclamation, 1995 April 23 (Box-folder 213: 8)
    Includes clippings and a chronology of GS's life
  - Photographs of GS at the International Women's Center awards, 1992 (Box-folder 213: 9)
- Italian resistance research materials, 1945 (Box-folder 213: 10)
  Includes "Impressioni dei primi 15 giorni successive al mio ritorno dell'Italia in Germania," author unknown
- Personal correspondence and holiday cards, 1990s (Box-folder 213: 11-12)
- Writing by GS on Amnesty International's Rome office, 1992 February 18 (Box-folder 213: 13)
- Writings by others, 1989-1993
  - Baez, Joan, 1993 January 30 (Box-folder 213: 14)
    Poem and sketch for GS
  - Sagan, Leonard, 1989, 1991 (Box-folder 213: 15)
    Trip reports for Eastern Europe and South Africa
- Human rights printed matter, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 213: 16)
- Joan Baez clippings, 1977-1995 (Box-folder 213: 17)
- Address book and notes, 1990s (Box-folder 214: 1)
- Amnesty International routine correspondence, internal documents and printed matter, 1974-1996 (Box-folder 214: 2-4)
- Aurora Foundation internal documents and printed matter, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 214: 5-6)
- Biographical file, 1974-1996 (Box-folder 214: 7-10)
  Includes clippings, Presidential Medal of Freedom press release and photographs of GS at a lectern
- Personal correspondence (Rose Styron, Leonard Sagan, Alfred A. Knopf publishers, Lidia Ghielmetti, and Barbara Piasecka Johnson), 1990s (Box-folder 214: 11-14)
  Includes photographs by Johnson of GS's garden
- "A Sentimental Journey," by Leonard Sagan, 1991 July 5-25 (Box-folder 214: 15)
- Photograph of Zbigniew Romaszewski, undated (Box-folder 214: 16)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1990s (Box-folder 214: 17-18)
- Amnesty International, 1986-1997
  - Board of Directors meeting agenda, 1996 December 13-15 (Box-folder 215: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 215: 2)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund proposals, correspondence, and press releases for the Children at War exhibit, 1996 (Box-folder 215: 3-4)
  - Negatives of Amnesty International event for Nancy Hersh, 1986 (Box-folder 215: 5)
  - Press clippings, 1996 (Box-folder 215: 6)
  - Printed matter, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 215: 7)
- Aurora Foundation meeting agenda and correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 215: 8-9)
- Personal correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 215: 10-11)
- Stanford commencement speech notes by GS, 1996 June 16 (Box-folder 215: 12)
- Women's Foundation and Global Fund for Women printed matter, 1996 (Box-folder 215: 13)
- Ahmed Kathrada interview by Harry Kreisler, 1996 November 8 (Box-folder 215: 14)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 215: 15-16)
- Amnesty International correspondence and 1996 speech by William Schulz, 1976, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 216: 1-5)
- Italian resistance research materials, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 216: 7-10)
  Includes photocopy of unidentified diary in Italian
- Amnesty International, 1993-1997
  - Board of Directors meeting agendas, comments and reports, 1996 September (Box-folder 217: 1)
  - Correspondence (Doan Long and Dianne Feinstein), 1993, 1997 (Box-folder 217: 2)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence and press releases, 1996 (Box-folder 217: 3)
  - Printed matter, 1997 (Box-folder 217: 4)
  - "Report and Decisions of the 22nd International Council of Amnesty International,", 1995 (Box-folder 217: 5)
- Aurora Foundation press releases and reports on Vietnam, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 217: 6)
- Biographical file, 1952, 1990-1996
  - Application for immigration visa and alien registration, photocopy, 1952 May 20 (Box-folder 217: 7)
  - Clippings, 199-1996 (Box-folder 217: 8)
- Personal correspondence (Barbara Piasecka Johnson, Mills College, and others), 1982, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 217: 9)
- Photographs of GS, Joan Baez, and Rose Styron, 1980s (Box-folder 217: 10-11)
- Leonard Sagan memorial service pamphlet, 1998 January 29 (Box-folder 217: 12)
- Italian resistance research, 1944-1945, 1965
  - L'Organizzazione Glass e Cross attraverso le Alpi: Retroscena diplomatici e di politica internazionale e finanziaria della lotta clandestine, by Edi Consolo, circa 1965 (Box-folder 217: 13)
  - Hans Deichmann memorandum, photocopy, 1945 (Box-folder 217: 14)
  - Memorandum on the Aosta Valley, photocopy, 1944 October 30 (Box-folder 217: 15)
    Includes photocopy of declassified British report on concentration camps
- Human rights clippings, 1979, 1990s (Box-folder 217: 16)
- Video tapes, 1997, undated
  - "GS on Cambodia,", undated (Box 217)
  - "Jefferson Awards 25th Anniversary Program,", 1997 (Box 217)
  - "National Italian American Foundation honors Ginetta Sagan,", 1997 (Box 217)
    General note
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007593
    This NIAF montage of photographs and moving image footage highlights their 1997 Lifetime Achievement Award in Human Rights winner Ginetta Sagan's life and accomplishments. Duration 4 minutes.
- Amnesty International, 1993-1998
  - Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 218: 1)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 218: 2)
  - Internal documents, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 218: 3-6)
    Includes minutes, reports and budgets
  - Memorandum to GS by Board of Directors, 1993 November 8 (Box-folder 218: 7)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence and internal documents, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 218: 8)
- Biographical clippings and photographs, 1982, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 218: 9-10)
  Includes photographs of GS with Clintons after Presidential Medal of Freedom ceremony
- Personal correspondence (Mary Felstiner and others), 1986-1998 (Box-folder 218: 11-12)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 218: 13-15)
- Amnesty International Board of Directors Meeting minutes, directory, and memoranda, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 219: 1-10)
- Amnesty International Board of Directors Meeting minutes, directory, memoranda and reports (cont'd.), 1994-1998 (Box-folder 220: 1-10)
- Sisters and Daughters Betrayed: The Sex Trade of Women and Girls: An International Conference on the Dynamics of Sexual Coercion, 1996 (Box-folder 220: 11)
- Amnesty International Board of Directors meeting minutes, directory, memoranda and reports, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 221: 1-10)
- Amnesty International, internal documents, correspondence, and printed matter, 1973-1999 (Box-folder 222: 1-3)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence, 1992, 1998 (Box-folder 222: 4)
- Biographical clippings, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 222: 5)
  Includes clipping from the Italian press
- Writings by GS, 1994, 1998
  - Ginetta Sagan: A Culinary Biography, 1994 (Box-folder 222: 6)
    Recipes and writings by GS and others
  - "Silence Is Complicity," speech delivered at a human rights conference in Warsaw, Poland, 1998 October (Box-folder 222: 7)
- Personal correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 222: 8)
- Photographs, 1985-1999
  - GS after car accident in Poland, 1987 October 11 (Box-folder 222: 9)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom ceremony and photographs of friends, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 222: 10)
    Includes photograph of Gemma Bustelli, wife of Guido Bustelli
  - GS at a protest for Amnesty International, 1999 April 5 (Box-folder 222: 11)
    Includes the poster held for the protest
  - GS with Philip Habib and Flora Lewis, 1990s (Box-folder 222: 12)
  - Joan Baez with Lech Wałęsa and Henryk Jankowski, 1985 (Box-folder 222: 13)
- Poland trip file, 1998 October (Box-folder 222: 14)
  Includes photographs of GS with student members of AI and a certificate of appreciation
- Video tapes, 1998, undated
  All are VHS
  - "Incite Hope: Amnesty International in Action,", 1998 (Box 222)
  - "Human Rights Now,", undated (Box 222)
- Amnesty International correspondence and internal documents, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 223: 1-2)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence and press releases, 1999 (Box-folder 223: 3)
- Appointment calendars, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 223: 4)
- Biographical profile of GS, 1999 July 1 (Box-folder 223: 5)
- Personal correspondence (Rose Styron, Elena Nightingale, Lidia Ghielmetti, Loring Sagan and Pico Sagan), 1994-1999 (Box-folder 223: 6)
- Poland trip file, 1998 October (Box-folder 223: 7)
  Includes photographs of GS with student members of AI
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 223: 8-9)
- "Consegna della cittadinanza onoraria ai coniugi Sagan, Brusson," video tape, 1997 June 18 (Box-folder 223: 10)
- Amnesty International internal documents, 1984 (Box-folder 224: 1)
- Matchbox, vol. 1, no. 4, 1975 (Box-folder 224: 2)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 224: 3)
- Biographical clippings, 1978-1996 (Box-folder 224: 4)
- Humanitas donation receipt, 1979 December 12 (Box-folder 224: 5)
- Writings by others, 1973-1991
  - Sean MacBride speech at the Conference for the Abolition of Torture, 1973 December (Box-folder 224: 6)
  - Leonard Sagan on GS's meetings with Guido and Gemma Bustelli, 1991 (Box-folder 224: 7)
  - Stuart "Pico" Sagan on human rights, 1980 June (Box-folder 224: 8)
- Vietnam and Latin America research materials, 1977-1991 (Box-folder 224: 9-15)
- [Not yet described] (Boxes 225-229)
- Declassified U.S. government records released in 2015, 1944-1945 (Box 227)
  Contains documents related to the OSS, including organizational charts of the of the Operational Group Command, and set of photocopied booklets on personal disguise.
- Ginetta Sagan Fund internal documents, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 230: 1-19)
- Italy trip, 1995 May-June (Box-folder 231: 1)
  Includes itinerary and correspondence by LS
- Human rights clippings on the Soviet Union, Vietnam, and Cambodia, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 231: 2-7)
- Amnesty International internal documents, correspondence, notes, and printed matter, 1986-1999 (Box-folder 232: 1-3)
  Includes a photograph of GS with Bill Clinton